# Amy Paslak

## 

## Summary

Stumbling into web design at a young age, I've been building apps, websites, and tools for over 15 years. I love solving problems and digging into code to determine how it works or could be improved. I absorb everything I can about my work and aspire to deliver elegant, scalable, and reliable code.

I love what I do, and aim to grow with like-minded engineers, building amazing tech.

# Experience

## Venmo — July 2019-present

#### MTS 2 Software Engineer

- Tech lead for Venmo's debit card. Crafted high-level design documentation, led feature discovery, and resolved intricate technical debt.
- Built comprehensive tooling for managing Venmo service deployments, with support for canaries, monitoring, and automatic rollback functionality using GitHub Actions.
- Lowered operational costs by load testing services and optimizing resource allocation.
- Migrated services from company maintained Kubernetes clusters to Amazon EKS.

#### MTS 1 Software Engineer

- Led several cross-functional teams to rewrite existing ledger functionality using Cassandra and gRPC for a more scalable, featurerich architecture.
- o Tech lead for Venmo's credit card. Remained knowledgeable of all project pieces while specializing in repayments domain.
- Led final stages of testing the Venmo credit card, which included representing Venmo engineering in partner meetings and developing a bug triage process which allowed us to track, manage, and fix over 600 tickets in a few weeks.
- Pioneered Venmo's adoption of GitHub Actions for CI/CD, establishing workflows and actions that were reused across the organization.

## Vibes Media — May 2012-July 2019

#### Senior Software Engineer / Team Lead

- Lead an agile team to maintain and improve an outdated CRM, built on Ruby/Rails with a Backbone.js and React front end.
- Championed large UI overhaul, upgrading the look and feel of the CRM up to date with modern styling and allowing the clean up unused and duplicated styles.
- Successfully migrated CRM from company-owned servers into AWS.

#### Software Engineer II / Team Lead

- Lead a team of contractors to update the CRM from Rails 2.3 & Ruby
  1.8.7 to Rails 3.2 & Ruby 2.1, with active development ongoing.
- Brief foray into contract work, where I built a small greeting card app and a lightweight conversation engine that integrated into the CRM.

## **Skills**

## Languages and Frameworks

- ∘ Python Django, Pytest
- Ruby Rails, Rspec, Selenium, Jekyll
- Javascript jQuery, Node.js, Backbone.js, Jasmine

## **Data Systems**

- o Databases MySQL, PostgreSQL, MongoDB, DynamoDB
- Data Stores Redis

#### Miscellaneous

- Event Driven Systems RabbitMQ, Kafka
- Application Monitoring DataDog, New Relic
- Infrastructure GitHub Actions, Docker, Kubernetes, AWS CDK, Jenkins

## Education

## Illinois Institute of Technology (IIT) — 2008-2012

**Bachelor of Science in Computer Science** 

- Minor in Psychology
- Information Security specialization
- Alpha Sigma Alpha sorority member